Maryam Mohammadi

@ maryam.mohammadi@uni-konstanz.de

Research Interests: My research interests are semantics, pragmatics and experimental studies, where theories can meet the real data. I mostly worked on polar questions and answers, bias, speech acts, and attitude predicates. I am also interested in programming to implement and develop algorithms from natural language to artificial languages.

EDUCATION

2024 Ph.D. Linguistics, Konstanz University (Germany)

Dissertation : Bias Conditions in Polar Questions and Answers : A study of Bias Effects in Farsi

2015 MA. Linguistics, Allame University (Iran)

Thesis: "var" Prefix in Farsi, a Cognitive Study in Word Formation

2013 BA. English Translation, Qazvin University (Iran)

2006 Associate Degree, Computer Science, Azad University (Iran)

◆ OTHER CERTIFICATES

ESSLLI Summer School

2021

> Modules : Commitment-based pragmatics (Bart Geurts), Dynamic inquisitive semantics (Jakub Dotlačil and Floris Roelofsen), Intensionalism and Propositionalism in Linguistic Semantics (Kristina Liefke and Ede Zimmermann)

Project Management Workshop

2020

> Modules : Classic and Agile project planning, Team works, Self-management, Software Trello.

DGfS Berlin Summer School

2019

> Modules: Questions (Maribel Romero), Speech Acts (Manfred Krifka), Statistics with R (Nicole Gotzner), Alternative Sets (Clemens Steiner-Mayr), Viewing Experimental Pragmatics from a Cognitive Science perspective (Ira Noveck).

Publications

- to appear Mohammadi, M., Koev, T. *Speaker Attitudes Predict Epistemic Biases in Polar Questions : Evidence from Farsi*, to appear in the proceedings of West Cost Conference of Formal Linguistics (WCCFL) 42, Berkeley University.
- to appear Mohammadi, M. *Non-Canonical Questions in Farsi*, to appear in The Oxford Handbook of Non-Canonical Questions, Oxford University Press.
 - Mohammadi, M., Romero, M. *Polar Particles in Farsi : Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse*, In the proceedings of Sinn und Bedeutun (SuB) 28.
 - 2023 Mohammadi, M. <u>Bias effect on response preference</u>, In the proceedings of Chicago Linguistic Society (CLS) 59.
 - Mohammadi, M. *mage as a bias particle in interrogatives*, In the proceedings of Inquisitiveness Below and Beyond the Sentence Boundary (IngBnB) 4 workshop, IWCS Conference.
 - Mohammadi, M. *Which stress is on response particles? An empirical study*, In the proceedings of Linguistic Society of America (LSA) 8.
 - 2022 Mohammadi, M. <u>A unified account of polar particles in Farsi</u>, In the proceedings of Linguistic Society of America (LSA) 7.
 - 2020 Koev, T., Bill, C., & Mohammadi, M. *Believe is strong but subjective : Experimental evidence from hedging*. In the proceedings of Sinn und Bedeutung (SuB) 25.

- 2019 Mohammadi, M. A Contrastive Analysis of Speech Act Conditionals as Indirect Answers in English and Farsi, Cambridge scholars publication.
- 2018 Hesse, Ch., Mohammadi, M., Langner, M., Fischer, J., Benz, A. & Klabunde, R. Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A system. In the proceedings of SemDial 22.

in progress Polar Response Particles in Farsi: Anaphoric Ambiguity.

PRESENTATIONS

- 2023 Polar Particles in Farsi: Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse, Semantics Workshop at the University of Massachusetts (Amherst).
- 2023 Polar Particles in Farsi: Sensitivity to the Scoreboard Model of Discourse, SuB 28, Bochum, Germany.
- 2023 'mage' as a bias particle in interrogatives, IWCS, IngBnB workshop, Nancy, France.
- 2023 Bias effect of response preference, CLS 59, Chicago University (poster presentation).
- 2023 mage: a Bias Sensitive Discourse Particle, NACIL 3, University of California, Los Angeles.
- 2023 Which Stress is on Response Particles? An empirical study, LSA Conference, Denver, Colorado.
- 2022 Which stress is on PRPs? SemDial 26, Technological University of Dublin, Ireland (poster presentation).
- 2022 A unified account of polar particles in Farsi, LSA Conference, Washington DC.
- Believe is strong but subjective: Experimental evidence from hedging, SuB 25 (with Koev and Bill). 2020
- 2018 A Contrastive Analysis of Speech Act Conditionals as Indirect Answers in English and Farsi, CoCoLaC conference, Helsinki University, Finland.
- 2018 From learning user types to generating biscuit conditionals, ComPrag Workshop, Bochum University.
- 2018 Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A system, SemDial 22, Aix-en-Provence, France (with Judith Fischer).
- 2018 Communicating an understanding of intention: Speech act conditionals and modified numerals in a Q/A system, DGfS Conference, Stuttgart University, Germany.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tutor

UMass (Amherst)

Visiting Scholar

2023

> Visiting the University of Massachusetts (Amherst) during the fall semester.

Konstanz Uni.

2020-2021

- > Tutoring course "Core Components of Language (B)", including syntax, semantics, pragmatics.
- > Tutoring course "Pragmatics I".

Ruhr University 2017-2019

Research assistant

- > Running a python application to generate indirect answers with speech act (/biscuit) conditionals.
- > Designing a decision-making model, using Bayesian probability.
- > Running a series of experiments in Amazon Mechanical Turk to find out English speakers' attitude towards the structure.
- > Data analysis with R.
- > Presenting the result in different conferences and workshops.

Chargoon Co.

Software developer

2015-2017

- > Developing a web-based software in HR system.
- > Team work for designing new features based on customers' requirements

Part time jobs

Programmer and Teacher

2010-2017

- > During my student years, I engaged in programming for various software companies.
- > I served as an English language teacher in several language institutes.



R&D I like to work on new topics and develop them with experimental studies. I conducted several experiments

in different frameworks e.g. Amazon MTurk, Testable, SurveyMonkey, as well as working on audio recording.

Data analysis I have experience in different statistical data analysis (e.g. lmer, GAMMs).

Programming R, Praat, LaTeX, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Delphi, WordPress, HTML, XML, CSS, SQL, Access

</> </> LANGUAGES

• Farsi : Native • English : Fluent • German : B2

66 References

Prof. Manfred Krifka

Leibniz-Centre General Linguistics (ZAS)

@ krifka@leibniz-zas.de

**** +49 30 20192 403

Prof. Maribel Romero

Department of Linguistics University of Konstanz

@ maribel.romero@uni-konstanz.de

4 +49 7531 882720

Dr. Todor Koev

Department of Linguistics University of Konstanz

@ todor.koev@uni-konstanz.de

**** +49 1573 2647920